

João Devson Mucavel

Nationality: Mozambican Date of birth: 09/06/1991 Gender: Male

Phone number: (+258) 844559091 **Phone number:** (+258) 868559091

Skype: joaodevsonm

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joão-devson-mucavel-116072aa/

GitHub: https://github.com/devassse

Website: http://joaodevson.keomagroup.com/

• Home: Av. Acordos de Lusaka Matola Gare - Nwamartibyana Q7, 1100 Maputo (Moz

ambique)

ABOUT ME

Working professionally as a Software Developer since 2015. Since then I have accumulated a lot of experience, especially in Web Development. Along the way I was able to learn in practice from my mistakes and from my more experienced colleagues. Which helped me succeed in other activities performed later. And I continue to look for new opportunities so that I can continue to progress professionally in my career and as a person.

Born on June 9, 1991, having completed basic education in 2006 and general secondary education in 2008. Graduated in *Computer Systems Programming* from the "Instituto Industrial e de Computação Armando Emílio Guebuza" in 2014 and having attended the Degree in *Systems Administration Information and Networks* at "Universidade São Tomás de Moçambique", (1st year only).

I plan to continue doing more certifications in addition to the Udemy training: *Javascript*, *Java*, *Python*, a little bit of *DevOps*.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer

ITGest Mozambique [04/2019 - Current]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

Web Applications Developer:

- Analysis and development of a Card and POS Clearing Settlement Solution (**4Liquidation**) for a customer a Bank.
- Worked on the implementation of a Service Desk solution at the Bank of Mozambique: *ID4Service*.
- Worked on the development of a User Support Management platform/solution (Service Desk *ID4Service*).
- Worked on the design project of a **Workflow** for Opening an Account and Contracting Means of Payment (Cards and Checks) for MOZA BANCO.
- Worked on a queue management platform (we call it *Ghahula*) to organize the meal times in the pantry, which is currently in use. Being accessible from QR Code.

Web developer

Brand Lovers [08/2018 - 03/2019]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

Web Developer:

• Website development (HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Php, Wordpress).

Software developer

Self-employed [07/2017 - Current]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

- Desktop Application Development (JavaSE);
- Interactive Solutions (IoT, VR & AR).

Web developer

FNB Moçambique [06/2017 – 07/2017]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

• Current website development and some improvements on existing Internet baking App.(30-day project in collaboration with Cloud Digital Arts)

Software developer

Cloud Digital Arts [04/2014 - 07/2017]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

- Website Development (HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Wordpress);
- Development of Technological and Interactive Solutions.

E-Learning Application Developer

SanTech, Lda [02/2014 – 06/2014]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

Intern:

• Development of SEGE - Electronic School Management System (ZK, JavaEE)

Infrastructure and Networking / Helpdesk

LAM - Linhas Aérias de Moçambique [08/2013 - 11/2013]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

Intern

- · Maintenance of Network Systems and Cabling;
- Helpdesk

Técnico de ar condicionado e refrigeração

[2011 - 2011]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

Repair and Maintenance of Refrigeration Devices - Air Conditioning Devices,

· Iceboxes, Freezers, Cold rooms

Inquier

[2010 - 2010]

City: Maputo

Country: Mozambique

Intercampus Inquisitor - Market Studies.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Computer Systems Programming

Armando Emílio Guebuza Industrial and Computing Institute [02/2011 - 07/2013]

Address: Maputo (Mozambique)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Português | Xangana | Ronga

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

DIGITAL SKILLS

Virtual Reality / Augmented reality: Vuforia / IoT/Mobile Device Management

SOCIAL AND POLITICAL ACTIVITIES

Social and communication skills

- Good communication skills with the work team acquired within the family and over the years in the job market.
- Improved public speaking skills gained while delivering religious public speeches.

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: C1

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organization skills

- Good ability to interact with employees in order to exchange experiences and doubts that may arise.
- Ability to work unsupervised as long as tasks are clearly defined.